《黑衣人》
妈的! 可恶的昆虫
Goddamn bugs.
真倒霉!
Oh, shit!
边界巡警
Oh, crap.
衰人尼克 真想不到
Well, Nick the Dick. What a surprise.
你从哪儿来的?
Where you coming from,Nick?
我去柯里纳钓鱼
Fishing in Cuernavaca.
好啊 看看你有什么鱼获
Sure. Let's take a look at your catch.
快
Come on.
我会把他们扔回去
I would've thrown them back.
你收多少钱? 每人一百? 二百?
What do you get? 100 bucks a head? 200?
希望你有储钱请律师! 你用的到的
Hope you saved it all for your lawyer. You'll need it.
交给我们处理
We'll take it from here.
你们是谁?
Who the hell are you?
移民局第6区的
INS, Division 6.
移民局第6区? 没听说过第6区
Division 6? I never heard of Division 6.
是吗?
Really?
你押在谁身上?
Who you betting on?
很难说
Tough call, Kay.
怎么了 你好吗?
好 好
婆婆 别担心
欢迎来到美国
你要去哪? 诺克里斯?
想找工作啊?
你呢 也是吗?
你也是?
很高兴在这儿见到你
你呢?
我可砸你的脸吗?
你长得真丑 不是吗?
你连一句西班牙话都不明白
我们找到了
We've got a winner here.
噢 我知道
Oh, I know.
其他人都可以走了
别动!
上车走吧
先生 你不能...
Sir, you can't...
别叫我先生 年轻人
Don't "sir" me, young man.
你根本不知道你在跟谁打交道
You have no idea who you're dealing with.
现在立刻上车!
我们要跟我们的朋友谈谈 你们先走
We'll chat with our friend. You hit the road.
继续保护我们 不受危险的外来者的骚扰
Keep on protecting us from the dangerous aliens.
听过第6区吗?
You ever hear of Division 6?
根本没有第6区
There is no Division 6.
这根本在胡说
This is bullshit.
没错
Hell, yeah.
看来你在不该在的地方 从巴士上掉下来
Looks like you fell off the bus in the wrong part of town.
我打赌你一定不是这附近的人
I'll bet you're not from anywhere near here.
米奇?
Mikey?
米奇 你什么时候出狱的?
Mikey, when they let you out of jail?
政治犯 没错
Political refugee.
你可知你犯了多少条约?
You know how many treaties you just violated?
- 1条? - 是7条
- One? - Try seven.
你把那头给我
You hand me that head.
把你的手和蹼举起来
Put up your arms and flippers.
妈的!
Shit!
开枪!
Shoot him!
- 那个 - 那个...
- "That." - That...
不是人类 没错 你身上还挂着些内脏
Was not human. I know. You got some entrails on you.
搞什么?
What the hell?
一切都在控制中
The situation's under control.
请留意一下
Give me your attention for a moment.
我乐意将事情对你们说
I'll tell you what happened.
这称为记忆清除器 是远方友人送的
This is called a neuralizer. It's a gift from friends from out of town.
红光能隔离...
This red eye isolates...
...脑中电子脉冲 尤其是记忆脉冲
...the brain's impulses, specifically the ones for memory.
从这开始...
Give me a splay burn on the perimeter...
...将方圆80公尺范围内...
...with holes at 40, 60, and 80 metres...
...不规则的烧焦 谢谢
...from right here. Thank you.
那样很好
That's good.
什么回事?
What's going on?
问得好
Excellent question.
答案就在这里
The answer you're looking for lies right here.
你是谁 到底是谁?
Who are you, really?
是谁?
Really?
我是你想像中的一个虚构人物
I am just a figment of your imagination.
妈的 真是好骗的品种
Damn, what a gullible breed.
说真的 你们没被炸死真侥幸
I'm serious. You're lucky to be alive after that blast.
什么爆炸?
What blast?
地下煤气管 天才
The underground gas main.
开枪前应注意点
You should exercise caution before firing...
我现在告诉你 尤其是你!
...l'll tell you that now. Especially you.
在你离开前先到 急诊室检查一下
Have yourself checked out with EMS before you leave.
刚才很抱歉
I'm sorry about back there.
总是会有意外的
It happens.
以前不会的
Didn't used to.
我的心有余 K 但是...
The spirit's willing, Kay...
...其他的部分...
...but the rest of me...
它们真漂亮 不是吗?
They're beautiful, aren't they?
那些星辰
The stars.
我们不只是光看星星了
We never just look anymore.
对
No
K 我告诉你...
I'll tell you, Kay...
...我会怀念追逐的日子
...I will miss the chase.
不 D...
No, Dee...
...你不会的
...you won't.
不许动!
Freeze!
我们是纽约警察 别动!
NYPD! Freeze!
交给你了
All yours, Edwards.
别动就是站住!
Freeze means stop!
是什么回事? !
What the hell?!
在纽约会下黑人雨
It just be raining black people in New York.
看到了吗?
Do you see this?
纽-约-警-察!
N-Y-P-D!
这代表了我会扭送你进警察局!
Means I will knock your punk-ass down!
他要来了!
He's coming!
他来了之后 我亦会拘捕他
Yeah, and when he gets here, I'll arrest his ass too.
你想被打?
You trying to catch a beat-down?
怎么了?
What's up?
他在路上了
He's coming.
他来是因为我失败了 他亦会杀了我
He's coming because I failed. Now he'll kill me.
你今天得罪了不少人 不是吗?
You pissing everybody off today, huh?
你不明白
You don't understand.
你们的世界就快被毁灭了
Your world's gonna end.
你是什么东西?
What are you?
当心会掉下去 小心
Watch that ledge. Watch the ledge.
下来 我们能把眼晴医好的 别担心
Come on down. We'll get those eyes fixed, don't worry.
等一下 让我跟你谈谈
Wait a minute. Let me talk to you!
我累得半死才可以为生
I work my butt off to make a living.
我只希望能回到一个整洁的家 有顿丰盛的晚餐...
All I want is to come home to a fat steak on the table...
...但我却得到这些 看起来像毒药
...but instead I get this. It looks like poison.
别拿走! 我正在吃呢! 这是毒药 不是吗?
Don't take that away! I'm eating that! It is poison, isn't it?
如果 我一点都不会惊讶...
I swear, I wouldn't be surprised if it was...
...你像一只被打太多或打的
...the way you skulk like a dog been hit too much,
不够的狗一样的闪闪躲躲!
or not enough!
我没办法决定
I can't decide.
你一点用都没有 碧姿
You're useless, Beatrice.
在这唯一可以做点事的东西 就是我的卡车
The only thing that pulls its weight around here is my goddamn truck!
早料到
Figures.
什么鬼玩意儿?
What the heck is it?
你滚进屋里去!
Get your big butt back in the house.
请把发射武器放在地上
Place projectile weapon on the ground.
要我丢下枪...
You can have my gun...
...除非我死了
...when you pry it from my dead fingers.
我接受你的建议
Your proposal is acceptable.
雅加 到底是怎么回事?
Edgar, what on earth was that?
糖
Sugar.
我从没见过糖会搞成那样
I've never seen sugar do that.
把糖给我
Give me sugar.
放在水里
In water.
多一点
More.
你的皮快掉下来了
Your skin is hanging off your bones.
这样好些吗?
Is that better?
"那罪犯眨了两对眼睑"
"The perpetrator blinked two sets of eyelids."
你指两眼一起眨?
Blinked with both eyes?
他先眨一对 然后再眨另外一对完全不同的
He blinked one set, then a completely different set.
像高灯和低灯那样
You know, like high beams and low beams.
那是在你说的那个武器...
Was that before or after he drew the weapon that you claim...
...蒸发成百万片...
...evaporated into a million pieces?
之后
After, sir.
为何都没有别的警官 看见这些事件?
Why is it that no other officers saw either of these events?
部分警察的腰围发胖
Some of them are soggy around the midsection.
这是他们赶不上的原因
They weren't able to keep up.
如果你是半个男人...
If you were half the man I am...
我就是你一半那么胖
I am half the man that you are.
你有什么问题?
What is your problem?
你缠住我了
You're in my face.
- 我想他把他从屋顶上丢下去 - 真的?
- I think he threw him off the roof. - You next.
我要跟你谈谈
I wanna talk to you.
10分钟 祝你好运
Ten minutes, you take your best shot, tough guy.
先运动10分钟 肥仔
Take 10 minutes on a StairMaster, you pudgy bastard!
我相信你 我是验尸官韦娜璐
I believe you. Laurel Weaver. Deputy Medical Examiner.
到验尸房找我 我有证据
Find me at the morgue. I'll show you.
等一下
Wait.
等一下!
Wait a minute!
你是检验无名尸的韦医生?
You're Dr. Weaver with the coroner's office working on the John Doe?
- 是的 - 请看这里 好吗?
- That's right. - Will you look at this, please?
今晚真精彩 不是吗?
Some night, huh?
今晚真精彩
Some night.
它们是腮 不是眼睑
They were gills, not eyelids.
腮 他在喘
Gills. He was out of breath.
你是谁?
Who are you?
他跟你说了什么吗?
Did he say anything to you?
他说世界末日到了
He said the world was coming to an end.
他有说什么时候吗?
Did he say when?
再看到那武器你会认出吗?
Would you recognize his weapon if you saw it again?
当然
Absolutely.
走 我们去兜风
Come on, let's take a ride.
慢着 我有一堆报告要写
Wait a minute. Look, I got tons of paperwork...
都写好了
It's all done.
干得好
Good work.
你真的是徒步去追那衰人? 不简单
You really ran this dude down on foot? That's tough.
非常不简单
That's double tough.
你到底是哪个部门的?
So who exactly are you with?
调查局? 国安局?
FBI? NSA?
我们负责监控地球上的外星人
I'm part of a bureau that licenses, monitors and polices aliens on Earth.
随便啦
Yeah, whatever.
到了
We're here.
这就是我们要去的地方?
This is where we're going?
这是积克的店
This is Jack Jeebs' spot.
他卖赃物但是不卖枪
He buys from chain-snatchers. Doesn't sell guns.
是吗?
Really?
听好
All right, look.
我进去问他几个问题 出来时我要你说实话
I'm gonna go in and put my thing down, but when I come out, I want answers.
进去问他几个问题
Okay, go put your thing down.
爱德华警官...
Officer Eduardo!
这怎么会在这? 我以为已经交给当局了
How did these get here? I thought I turned them in.
听说你有比偷来的劳力士更抢手的
I hear you're into something hotter than stolen Rolexes.
我也贩卖毒品 但我喜欢在这儿做生意的时间
I deal crack, but I still work here. I love the hours.
我指的是枪 耍聪明!
I'm talking about guns, smart-ass! Weird ones.
你眼见的 我只有这么些货了
Come on! What you see is what I got.
给他看进口货
Show him the imports, Jeebs.
K 你好吗?
Hey, Kay. How are you?
- 给他看进口货 - 我很久没卖进口货了
- Show him the imports. - I got out of that business.
为何骗我?
Why do you lie to me?
等一下
Hold on a second.
数到3
I'll count to three.
他会开枪的 这个人看起来不太稳定
He'll do it, Jeebs. That man does not look stable.
那家伙这样是很疯狂的
You know what? He's crazy when he's like this.
他总是这样子 去按摩一下
He's always crazy. Get a massage.
搭船旅游...
Take a cruise...
- 丢下枪 把手放在头上 - 我警告过他了
- Drop the weapon. - I warned him.
丢下枪!
Drop the weapon!
- 我们警告他了 - 我要开枪了
- You warned him. - I'll kill you.
粗鲁的讨厌鬼!
You insensitive jerk!
你可知那样有多痛吗?
Do you have any idea how much that stings?
拿出货来 否则再补一枪
Show us the merchandise, or you'll lose another head.
爱德华先生...
Mr. Edwards...
那把 中间那把
There, the one in the middle.
你把将反射碳化能量围换枪...
You sold a reverberating carbonizer with mutate capacity...
...卖给没执照的塞波人!
...to an unlicensed cephalopoid! You piece of...
他看起来像是好人
He looked okay to me.
他要暗杀的对象是谁?
It was for an assassination. The target?
不知道
I don't know.
- 可恶! - 我不知道!
- Goddamn it! - I don't know!
全部枪都充公
All that's confiscated.
你搭下班船离开这儿 不然我会杀了你
Be on the next transport off this rock, or I shoot where it don't grow back.
我会再回来问你劳力士的事
And I'm gonna be back to talk about them Rolexes.
在找问题的症结吗?
Searching for a handle on the moment?
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
我能做的是...
The only comfort I can offer...
...保证明天你什么都忘了
...is my promise that tomorrow you won't remember a thing.
这种事怎么可能说忘就忘
That's not exactly some shit you forget.
见过这东西吗?
Ever seen one of these?
她望着她丈夫...
She looks over to her husband...
...把它放在大腿上说:
...then sets it down in her lap and says:
"甜心 它在吃我的爆壳"
" Honey, this one's eating my popcorn."
明白吗?
Get it?
它在吃...
This one's eating...
我得走了 谢谢你的春卷
Gotta go. Thanks for the egg rolls.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你是谁?
Who are you?
知道我对龙舌兰酒的意见了吧? 你个聪明的年轻人
See what I mean about tequila? You're very bright.
不要喝太多的酒
But you need to lay off the sauce.
明天一早九点见
I'll see you bright and early, 9:00.
来不来...
Be there...
...随便你
...or be square.
(黑超特警组)
(贝利街504号)
看看这里
Well, well, well.
尽管搬进来 不是这样吗? 当这是自己的家?
Moving right in, are we? Think we own the place?
我有张驱逐通知单
I got an eviction notice for you.
你在这里做什么?
Just what exactly do you think you're doing here?
处理你的害虫问题
Taking care of your pest problem.
除虫害?
Pest problem?
虫害?
Pest?
这儿到处是害虫
You got a hell of an infestation.
我看见它们泛滥成灾了
You know, I've noticed an infestation here.
在我的视线范围内 到处是 浮垢...
Everywhere I look, nothing but undeveloped, unevolved...
...让我深信它们这高等族群...
...barely conscious pond scum...
...为了它们短暂
...totally convinced of their own superiority...
而无价值的生命...
...as they scurry about their short...
...到处逃窜
...pointless lives.
你不想除去他们吗?
Don't you wanna get rid of them?
非常想
In the worst way.
(桥梁隧道管理局)
有事吗?
Help you?
有人给我这张名片...
This dude gave me this card...
坐升降机
Elevator.
你迟到了 坐下
You're late. Sit down.
我叫Z
My name is Zed.
请你们来因为你们是佼佼者
You're all here because you're the best.
海军 空军 海军特种部队
Marines, Air Force, Navy SEALs,
军方特击队员 纽约警察
Army Rangers, NYPD.
我们要选出一人
We want one of you.
只选一人
Just one.
接下来 要经由一些简单测试...
What will follow is a series of simple tests...
...去测验体力 注意力及精力
...for motor skills, concentration, stamina.
有人有问题
I see we have a question.
抱歉 也许已经问过了...
I'm sorry, maybe you already answered this but...
...我们为何来这里?
...why are we here?
你说
Son.
中尉泽克 西点军校优等生
Lieutenant Jensen. West Point graduate with honours.
我们来是因为你需要 佼佼者中的精英!
We're here because you want the best of the best of the best, sir!
有什么好笑的?
What's so funny, Edwards?
你的这个男孩 美国上校
Your boy, Captain America, here.
"佼佼者中的精英"
"The best of the best of the best, sir!"
"而且是优等的"
"With honours."
他兴奋异常...
He's just really excited...
...却不明白所为何来
...and has no clue why we're here.
对我而言很好笑
That's just very funny to me.
虽然你们都没笑
Y'all ain't laughing, though.
好了 开始吧
Okay, let's get going.
你们要用这张桌子吗?
Wanna get down on this?
怎么回事?
Edwards, what happened?
我迟疑了
Hesitated.
我可以知道为什么 要杀小蒂芬妮?
May I ask why you felt little Tiffany deserved to die?
她最具威胁性
She was the only one that seemed dangerous.
何以见得?
How'd you figure that?
本来想射挂在路灯上的那个...
I was gonna pop this guy hanging from the light...
...但是他只是在运动
...but he's just working out.
如果我在运动时 被逮捕会是什么滋味?
How'd I feel if somebody bust my ass while I'm on the treadmill?
然后我看到这个在嘶叫的怪物...
Then I saw this snarling beast.
...因为看到他手里拿了卫生纸 所以我知道...
I noticed he had a tissue in his hand and realized...
...他在打喷嚏
...he's not snarling, he's sneezing.
那不造成威胁
Ain't no threat there.
我看到蒂芬妮
Then I saw Tiffany.
我在想 一个8岁白人的女孩 半夜在...
8-year-old white girl, middle of the ghetto...
...全是怪物的街上 手上拿着量子学书...
...bunch of monsters at night with quantum physics books?
...她一定有些不好的企图
She about to start some shit.
这种书对她来说太深了
Those books are way too advanced for her.
对我而言 她很可疑
If you ask me, she's up to something.
老实说 关于这点 我觉得你不要这么针对我
I'd appreciate it if you eased up about it.
还是要我向她道歉?
Or do I owe her an apology?
至少射得很准 不是吗?
Good shot, though, right?
他不好管
He has a problem with authority.
我也是
So do I.
但他能徒步追捕塞波人 老大
But this kid ran down a cephalopoid on foot, boss.
那要很强悍才行的
That's gotta be tough enough.
希望你知道自己做什么
Let's hope you know what you're doing.
各位...
Gentlemen, congratulations.
...恭喜 多年的政府训练没有白费
You're everything we expect from years of government training.
各位跟我来 最后一项
If you'll just follow me, we have one more test to administer.
是视力测验
An eye exam.
你去哪里?
Where are you going?
究竟什么回事?
What the hell is all this?
在1950年左右 政府成立了经费不足的机构...
In the 1950s, the government started an underfunded agency...
...简单而好笑的目的只是要
...with the laughable purpose of establishing contact...
与外星人取得联系
...with a race not of this planet.
各位看这仪器末端
Look at the end of this device.
除了外星人之外 人类都把这当成笑话...
Everyone thought the agency was a joke, except the aliens...
...但在1961年时 外星人在纽约有首次的接触
...who made contact on March 2, 1961 outside New York.
第一天晚我们有九个人
There were nine of us the first night.
七名特工 一名天文家...
Seven agents, one astronomer...
...及一个迷途的男孩
...and a dumb kid who'd gotten lost.
噢 你给那个高个子献花
You brought that tall man some flowers.
这边走
This way.
他们是一群银河系的难民
They were a group of intergalactic refugees.
想把地球当做无家可归者 的政治庇护所
Wanted Earth as an apolitical zone for creatures without a planet.
你看过《北非谍影》吗?
You ever see Casablanca?
是一样的 只是没有纳粹党
Same thing, except no Nazis.
我们同意 而且藏匿了他们降落的证据
We agreed and concealed all evidence of their landing.
所以这些是真的飞碟 世界博览会只是个掩饰
So these are real flying saucers and the World's Fair was a cover-up?
还有什么其他理由在皇后区?
Why hold it in Queens?
每年到达的非人类越来越多而且 隐藏在我们之中生活
More nonhumans arrive every year and live among us in secret.
我不是要改变话题
Not to change the subject,
你最后一次做脑电图是什么时候?
but when was the last time you got a CAT scan?
- 半年前 是公司规定的 - 你该做另一个预约
- Six months ago. It's company policy. - Make another appointment.
告诉Z我玩得很高兴...
Tell your boy Zed I had an absolutely wonderful time...
...而且要谢谢你 并请告诉我出口在哪儿
...and thank you for everything, but show me the door.
我要喝咖啡 你要吗?
All right. I'm getting some coffee. You want some?
不 不要了 谢谢
No, thank you, I'm fine.
你们好吗?
How you doing?
嗨 K
Hi, Kay.
- 那是不是没咖啡因的? - 是维尼斯肉桂味
- That's not decaf, is it? - Viennese cinnamon.
别告诉我只有粉末的奶精了 我最不喜欢那种了
Don't tell me we only got powdered stuff for cream. I hate it.
好的 好
Well, that's good. Good. Good.
你们相处的愉快吧?
You guys getting along all right?
工作别太辛苦
Don't work too hard.
你真的不要咖啡?
Sure you don't want some coffee?
事情是这样的
Here's the deal.
地球上约有一千五百名外星人
At any given time, there are around 1500 aliens on the planet.
大部分居住在曼哈顿
Most of them here in Manhattan.
大部分守规矩 只想谋生活
Most of them are decent. Just trying to make a living.
- 计程车司机? - 不是你所想像的那么多
- Cab drivers? - Not as many as you'd think.
大多数的人类一点也不知道 也不想知道
Humans, for the most part, don't have a clue. Don't want one.
他们很高兴 以为自己掌握一切
They're happy. They think they have a good bead on things.
为何要保密呢? 人们很聪明 可以应付的
People are smart. They can handle it.
一个人是聪明
A person is smart.
众人是愚蠢 易慌张 和危险的动物
People are dumb, panicky, dangerous animals, and you know it.
1500年前 每个都人知道...
1500 years ago, everybody knew the Earth was...
...地球是宇宙的中心
...the centre of the universe.
五百年前 每个人都知道地球是平的
500 years ago, everybody knew the Earth was flat.
十五分钟前 你知道在地球上只有人类
And 15 minutes ago, you knew that people were alone on this planet.
想想明天...
Imagine what you'll know...
...你会知道什么
...tomorrow.
- 有什么坏处? - 坏处?
- What's the catch? - The catch?
坏处就是你会切断 和人类的接触
The catch is, you will sever all human contact.
没人知道你存在...
Nobody will ever know you exist anywhere...
...没有
...ever.
我让你考虑到日出
I'll give you to sunrise to think it over.
值得吗?
Is it worth it?
是值得的...
Yeah, it's worth it.
...若你够坚强
If you're strong enough.
你好吗?
What's up, pops?
我要加入...
I'm in...
...因为这儿有更深层的事 会发生
...because there's some next-level shit going on here.
但首先我要你明白某些事情
Before y'all beam me up, there's a few things to understand.
首先 是你选我...你知道我的长处
First off, you chose me, so you recognize the skills.
我不想人叫我为小子 明白吗?
I don't want nobody calling me "son" or " kid" or "sport." Cool?
随便 油嘴
Cool. Whatever, slick.
但我要告诉你关于你的长处
But I need to tell you something about all your skills.
现在你看到的是...
As of right now, they mean precisely...
...这些家伙
...dick.
- 此行的目的? - 外交任务
- Purpose of trip? - Diplomatic mission.
停留时间?
Duration of stay?
吃午餐
Lunch.
有水果或蔬菜吗?
Any fruits or vegetables?
你要远离那家伙
You wanna stay away from that guy.
它脾气很坏
He's grouchy.
在旅行了17兆里后又在海关 滞留三小时
Three hours in customs after a 17-trillion-mile trip...
都会让人脾气暴躁
...will make anyone cranky.
我们向政府哪部门报告?
What government branch do we report to?
- 没有 他们有太多问题 - 谁支付这一切?
- None. They ask too many questions. - Who pays for this?
我们拥有几项仪器的专利
We hold patents on a few gadgets we confiscated from out-of-state visitors.
魔术帖 微波炉 抽脂手术
Velcro, microwave ovens, liposuction.
这装置很有趣
This is a fascinating gadget.
不久就能取代CD
It'll replace CDs soon.
那样我就又能买《白色相簿》了
I'll have to buy the White Album again.
这很好玩 是宇宙翻译机 我们不该有的
That's fun. A universal translator. We're not even supposed to have it.
人的思想原始得...
Human thought is so primitive. It's looked upon...
...在别的星河认为是 会传染的疾病
...as an infectious disease in some galaxies.
这会使你引以为荣的
That kind of makes you proud.
这是什么东西?
What's this?
冷静
Just be calm!
别慌张!
Relax!
小心你的头!
Watch your head!
给他点冰吧!
Someone get him some ice!
走开! 它向你飞来时快走开!
Look out! Move! Just move when it's coming at you!
糟糕!
Damn!
我会赔偿的!
I'll pay for that!
它在1977年导致纽约大停电
This thing caused the 1977 New York blackout.
是大吸引者的玩笑
Practical joke by the Great Attractor.
他认为很有趣
He thought it was funny.
各位 抱歉了
Sorry, y'all.
那是意外 对不起
It was a accident. Sorry.
观察室 我们工作的中心
Observation, the heart of our endeavour.
来介绍一下 双胞胎 波和卜
Meet the twins, Blblup and Bob.
这地图显示地球上 每个外星人的所在
This map shows the location of every alien on Earth.
有些会一直被监视
Some are under constant surveillance.
荧幕上的全是外星人
Everyone on those screens is an alien.
在公众场合他们很正常 但在私底下...
In public, they're as normal as you are, but in private...
你知道了
You'll get the idea.
老天
Oh, man.
不合理 是吗?
Doesn't make any sense, right?
不 合情合理
Well, no, it makes perfect sense.
我三年级时 人人都以为我疯了...
In third grade, everyone said I was crazy, but I knew our teacher...
...但我知道老师 一定是金星来的
...had to be from Venus or something.
魏太太其实来自木星的...
Ms. Edelson. Jupiter, actually. Well, one of the moons.
其中之一月球
...revolve.
各位...
Class...
...安静并请注意!
...be quiet and pay attention!
若我要再
If I have to tell you...
说一次...
...one more time...
穿上吧
Let's put it on.
穿什么?
Put what on?
你穿的最后一套衣服
The last suit you'll ever wear.
你只能穿...
You will dress only in attire specially sanctioned...
...黑超特警特定的服装
... by MiB Special Services.
要依照我们给你的身分...
You'll conform to the identity we give you...
...到指定地方吃饭 到指定地方居住
... eat where we tell you, live where we tell you.
现在开始...
From now on...
...你没有任何的身分记号
... you'll have no identifying marks of any kind.
你绝不能突出
You will not stand out in any way.
你整体的形象被塑造成...
Your entire image is crafted...
...不能留给所遇上的人 任何印象
... to leave no lasting memory with anyone you meet.
你是谣言...
You are a rumour, recognizable only as...
...对人家来说只是似曾相似 又不认得
... deja vu and dismissed
just as quickly.
你不存在 甚至没有出生
You don't exist. You were never born.
你的名字是无名氏
Anonymity is your name.
不作声是你的语言
Silence, your native tongue.
你不再是制度一部分
You're no longer part of the system.
你在制度之上 之外
You are above the system. Over it.
超越了它
Beyond it.
我们是他们
We're "them. " We're "they. "
我们是黑超特警
We are the Men in Black.
我和你的分别就是...
You know what the difference is between you and me?
...我穿起来更好看
I make this look good.
你和我开车去走走
We're gonna go for a little ride.
我先把你放下 爸爸很快回来
I'll put you down here for a minute, and Daddy will be right back.
好了 我们可以起程了
Okay, now we're ready to go for a little ride.
去见爸爸的朋友 你会很喜欢他
We'll meet one of Daddy's friends, and you'll like him.
让我们看看
Okay, let's see.
...被罢免的主管...
Bee, we got the deposed sur-prefect of Singalee...
...今晚在波兰外降落
...touching down in the forest outside Portland tonight.
- 类似人类的? - 你想的美 带着海绵
- Humanoid? - You wish. Bring a sponge.
这是昨晚留下的红色警告
Here. Red letter from last night.
纽约上州有未经批准的降落
We had an unauthorized landing in upstate New York.
K 留意此事发展
Keep your ears open on this one.
我们不是主持星际派对
We're not hosting an intergalactic kegger down here.
有人逃走了
We got a skimmer.
移民来的外星人越区 是谁?
Landed alien out of zone. Who is it?
烈擎
Redgick.
他不能离开曼哈顿...
He's not cleared to leave Manhattan, but he's out of town...
...但他现时离城 被堵在公路上
...stuck on the New Jersey turnpike.
你为什么不带小子去?
Take junior with you.
这对他来说是热身的好机会
This is a good one for him to warm up on.
去对付他们
Go get him, tiger.
"我们不是主持星际派对"
"We're not hosting an intergalactic kegger."
他只是...
He just...
全宇宙有无限的科技 而我们却利用这烂车...
Unlimited technology from the whole universe, and we cruise around...
...来做交通工具
...in a Ford POS.
绑好安全带
Fasten your seat belt.
你的人际关系还要加强
We gotta work on your people skills.
若你礼貌一点 所得的反应会较好
You'd get a better reaction if you were polite.
请绑好安全带
Fasten your seat belt, please.
好 你有受伤吗?
Good. Did you hurt yourself?
你千万别碰那红色按钮 小子
The red button there, kid. Don't ever touch the red button.
好 老爹 七十二元
All right, pop, that'll be $72 there.
好吧 宝贝 让我付钱给无礼的司机
Okay, sweetie, let me pay the impolite driver.
抱歉我迟到了 这星球的司机很差
陛下 你很危险
对啊 而且每次都 多收车资
有个虫降落了 我们要把你从这星球送走
有个昆虫? 他一定知道我为何会在这
我们想他是知道的
那是我所想要的吗?
不 只是给你孩子的 钻石
有空进食吗?
当然 我已替你点了菜
六号上菜!
Six is up!
艾文呢?
Where is lvan?
我让他休息了
Gave him a break.
为亚基伦帝国 继续统治干杯
为银河系安全干杯
你可以杀我们 但你找不到银河系
You can kill us both, but you will not find the Galaxy.
你说对一件事
You're right about one thing.
你哪里也不能去
You're not going anywhere.
请出示执照及登记证书
Your licence and registration, please.
请出示另外那种执照及登记证书
Like to see your other licence and registration, please.
你只限在曼哈顿活动 你去哪儿 烈擎?
You're restricted to Manhattan. Where are you going, Redgie?
是我太太 她... 看
It's my wife. She's... Well, look.
问题不大
No big deal.
好 你跟我来 烈擎
Okay, you come with me, Redge.
你应付这个
And you handle this.
什么? 我?
What?! Me?
- 你只要接就好了 - 他知道他在做什么吗?
- You just catch. - Does he know what he's doing?
当然 让他做吧
He does it all the time. Let him work.
哎哟 老天! 所以...
Damn, man!
有东西伸出来了!
Something's peeking!
你却先往城外去 到底什么事?
You're headed out of town.
- 我们去见别人 - 是谁?
- We're meeting someone. - Who?
- 是一艘船 - 我今天没有看到有核准离境的资料
- It's a ship. - I saw no departure clearance.
你没有?
You didn't?
这是紧急事件
It's an emergency.
你做得很好 好样的!
You're doing fine!
有什么紧急事? 为何突然要离开星球?
What kind of emergency? What's the rush to get off the planet?
我们只是不喜欢 我们的那一区了
We don't like the neighbourhood anymore.
有些是新来的人...
Some of the new arrivals...
新来的? 和昨晚坠毁的有关吗?
New arrivals? Have anything to do with the crasher last night?
对不起 小姐!
Excuse me, miss!
噢 天啊!
Oh, man.
Oh, man!
你看
Look.
噢 天啊
Oh, man!
恭喜 烈擎 它是个...
Congratulations, Redge. It's a...
...乌贼
...squid.
他其实是...
You know, it's...
...非常的...
...actually kind of...
...可爱
...cute.
刚才有什么不正常的地方?
Anything about that seem unusual?
是什么把他吓成这样...
What would scare Redgick so badly...
...要带着新生儿去冒险?
...that he'd risk a warp jump with a newborn?
我们追查资料吧
We'll check the hot sheets.
教宗是个父亲 令人震惊的证据在内
These are "hot sheets"?
这就是资料?
Best investigative reporting on Earth.
地球上最佳的调查报告
Read The New York Times if you want. They get lucky sometimes.
想不到你在超市卖的 八卦报导上找线索
Cannot believe you're looking for tips in the supermarket tabloids.
不是在找
Not " looking for."
找到了
Found.
(外星人偷走了我丈夫的皮囊)
- 慢着 别急  - 为什么?
- Wait a minute, slow down. - Why?
给她点时间让她想歪了 让调查更容易些
Give her time to get the wrong impression. Makes it smoother.
有何贵干?
Can I help you?
我是联邦调查局的文特警 他是毕特警
Yes, ma'am. I'm Agent Manheim, this is Agent Black, FBI.
想问有关访客的事
We'd like to talk about your visitor.
你们也要拿我开玩笑?
Gonna make fun of me too?
调查局的人没有可令人察觉的 幽默感
No, we do not have a sense of humour we're aware of.
我们可以进来吗?
May we come in?
请进
Sure.
- 谢谢 - 要柠檬水吗?
- Thank you. - Lemonade?
噢 好的
Oh, yes, please.
警察局长亲自来这...
The chief of police came to the house...
...做了一个全面的调查
...and did an investigation.
拿走警方报告 还写下我说的一切...
Took a police report and writ down everything I said...
...但不相信我说的 任何一句话
...not believing one thing I said.
而且还有点在取笑我
Sort of poking fun at me.
他们问我 若他被谋杀...
He asked me, " If he was murdered...
...怎么能走进屋子?
...how was he able to walk back in the house?"
我得承认这把我问倒了
I gotta admit to you that that one got me stumped.
我了解雅加 那人不是雅加
I tell you, I know Edgar, and that wasn't Edgar.
就像有东西在穿雅加的身体
It was like something was wearing Edgar.
像是外衣...
Like a suit...
...一件"雅加"外衣
...an Edgar suit.
那人变外星人前已很丑
Dude was that ugly before he was an alien.
对不起
I'm sorry.
继续
Go on.
不管怎样...
Anyway...
...我醒来他己离去
...I come to and he's gone.
他说了什么吗?
He say anything?
有 他向我要水喝
Yes. He asked me for some water.
糖水
Some sugar water.
糖水?
Sugar water?
我记得 因为很怪异...
I remember that right. I thought that that was odd...
...他要糖水而不是...
...that he asked me for sugar water and not lemonade or ice water...
...水或自来水...
...or regular water...
...水或冰水
...tap water.
好 碧姿 没有外星人
All right, Beatrice. There was no alien.
那道闪光不是飞碟
The flash of light was not a U.F.O.
是上升煤气团被金星反射
Gas was trapped in a thermal pocket and refracted the light from Venus.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你洗掉她记忆再编个新的?
That thing erases her memory, and you just make up a new one?
这是记忆清除器
A standard-issue neuralizer.
你编那么烂的故事?
That weak-ass story is the best you came up with?
好 附加说明...
All right. On a more personal note...
...雅加跟他前任女友跑了
...Edgar ran off with an old girlfriend.
你搬去跟你妈住一阵就好了
You'll stay with your mama...
你觉得这样会更好
...and decide you're better off.
反正他对你那么坏
Yeah, because he never appreciated you anyway.
事实上 告诉你
In fact, you know what?
是你甩了他 他走了...
You kicked him out. And now that he's gone...
...你可以买漂亮衣服
...you'll go in town, find yourself some nice dresses.
买双鞋 也许去做面部按摩
Get yourself some shoes. Find somewhere you could get a facial.
而且...快找人来重新装修 这儿很不济
And hire a decorator to come in here quick because... damn!
我何时才能...
When do I get my own flashy...
...有记忆清除器?
...memory messer-upper?
等你长大之后
When you grow up.
拜托不要是绿色
Please. Not green.
该死!
Oh, damn!
你知道哪种 外星人是流绿汁...
Do you know which alien leaves a green spectral trail...
...喝糖水的?
...and craves sugar water?
那是昨晚机智问答的题目 答案是...
That was on Jeopardy last night. Damn, Alex said it was...
Z 虫族入侵
Zed, we have a bug.
意思是... 我们不喜欢虫族?
So... What? We don't like bugs?
虫族制造大屠杀
Bugs thrive on carnage, tiger.
它们消耗 骚扰其他种族...
They consume, infest, destroy, live off the death of other species.
你童年时被虫咬过?
You were stung as a child, right?
想像一个超大蟑螂 它力大无穷...
Imagine a giant cockroach with unlimited strength...
...劣等生物本性 易怒...
...a massive inferiority complex, and a real short temper...
...穿雅加的皮横行曼哈顿
...is terrorizing Manhattan Island in a new Edgar suit.
听起来有趣吗?
That sound like fun?
该怎么做?
What's the move?
只要虫族在城里 我们就要去殓房监视
With a bug in town, we'll watch the morgues.
3号尸体要放哪里?
Where do you want contestant number 3?
放在那就行了
Just leave it there.
那只猫怎么回事?
What's with the cat?
这只猫有个麻烦 在这签名
There's a problem with the cat. Sign here.
- 什么麻烦? - 你的麻烦
- What's the problem with the cat? - It's your problem.
我讨厌活人
I hate the living.
开始吧!
Shall we?
噢 我的老天!
Oh, my God!
朋友 你是什么?
Buddy, what are you?
解剖时尸温约112华氏度...
Subject was approximately 112 degrees at time of autopsy...
...表示体温上升了
...indicating a temperature increase.
验尸者想由直肠量体温 却找不到直肠
Examiner tried to verify this rectally, but the subject had no rectum.
这情况真...
Which is really...
怪
Weird.
我们是卫生署的文医生 与白医生
I'm Dr. Leo Manville, Department of Public Health. This is Dr. White.
你们一定没有家庭生活
You must not have a home life.
我们最近在监视这殓房 近来有何异常状况?
We watch the morgues carefully. You have something unusual?
有 三重凶杀案
I'd say so. Triple homicide.
第一个还算正常 除了被折成两半之外
The first body was normal, except he was broken in half.
当我解剖了另两个尸体...
But when I opened up the other two, well...
我带你去看
Let me show you.
他的骨骼架构有异于常人
There's a skeletal structure unlike anything I've seen.
我查看这个
I'll have a look at it.
你们去查看另一个尸体
You and Dr. Weaver check the other body.
往这边走
This way, doctor.
这个更怪
This one's even stranger.
我做腹部解剖 我由胃开始
I did a laparotomy. I started with the stomach.
我们可以由食道开始 或看你想从哪里开始
But we can start with the gastroesophageal junction.
就照你的方法
Let's start wherever you started at.
没问题
Okey-dokey.
- 这是你的猫? - 现在是了
- Is this your cat? - It is now.
跟着尸体来的 探手进去
It came in with the body. Dive right in.
他不会在意的
I'm sure he won't mind.
你的眼神很迷人
You have really pretty eyes.
谢谢
Thank you.
感觉到了吗?
Feel that?
摸到幽门了? 推过一旁
Where the pyloric junction would be? Push it aside.
有什么不对? 胃 肝 肺...
Notice anything strange? Stomach, liver, lungs...
没有 都很好
Nope, all fine.
器官都不见了
They're all missing.
当然
Of course.
我首先便注意到了
That's obviously the first thing I noticed.
我的意思是说 里面没有...
What I was pointing out is the fact that there are no...
...碎片...
...pieces...
...存在
...of them left.
你知道 那些器官都...
You know, so they're intact...
是完整的不见了... ...是肯定的
...wherever they are whole. That we can be sure of.
我们见过吗?
Have we met before?
我有个似曾相识的感觉
I'm having a feeling of dejavu.
- 我也是 - 真的?
- Yeah, me too. - Really?
想知道我在想什么吗? 但别告诉他
Wanna know what I think? Don't tell him.
他太紧张了 我认为那不是尸体
He's under enough stress. I don't think it's a real body.
我认为这是种运输工具 或是类似的
I think it's some kind of transport unit for something else.
问题是 什么?
The question is, what?
这是不是把你吓坏了?
Is this freaking you out?
不
No, girl.
你知道有时候我想做什么?
You know what I like to do sometimes when it's late?
不知
No
白医生
Dr. White.
失陪
Excuse me.
怎样?
What do you think?
很有趣 她很喜欢死人...
Interesting. She got a "Queen of the Undead" thing going...
我是指"身体"
Of the body.
身材很劲
Great body.
我指尸体
The dead body.
你最好去看看
You have to look at that thing.
认得他吗?
You recognize him?
在总部见过他 只是更死像
He looks like the big guy I saw at headquarters, only deader.
是什么杀了他?
What killed him?
虫族?
A bug?
她在叫你
You're up, slugger.
看这个
Look at this.
这是什么?
What the hell is that?
必须...
Must...
避免...
To prevent...
...争夺
...contest.
你想说什么?
What are you saying?
避免...
To prevent...
...挣扎?
...struggle?
...避免...
To prevent...
战争?
War?
战争
War.
银河系...
The Galaxy...
...是在...
...is on...
...猎户座的...
...Orion's...
...带...
...be...
怎么说?
What is word?
床?
The bed?
带? 猎户座星带?
Belt? Orion's belt?
"避免战争 银河系在猎户座星带上"
"To prevent war, the Galaxy is on Orion's belt."
什么意思?
What the hell does that mean?
那个叫...
Doctor...
...什么的 过来
...whatever, come here.
叫什么的? 你们不是卫生署派来的
Dr. Whatever? You guys aren't really from the Department of Health.
洛辛保! 可恶!
Rosenberg. Damn!
亚基伦人不会喜欢这个 他是皇族的成员之一
The Arquillians won't like this. He was one of the royal family.
这是外星人...
This is an alien...
...你们是政府官员 来掩饰实情的
...and you're from a government agency keeping it under wraps.
他说避免战争 银河系在猎户座星带上
He said, "To prevent war, the Galaxy is on Orion's belt."
这就对了 你要怎么解释纽约?
How else do you explain New York?
我当时在计程车 这个人
I was in this cab, and this guy was...
银河系在猎户座星带上 听起来没道理
"Galaxy on Orion's belt" makes no sense.
大头里的小人是这么说 对吗?
That's what the little dude inside the big dude's head said, right?
可恶! 你洗掉了她的记忆
Damn, man! You did the flashy thing already.
不论你们是谁 出示身份证
Whoever you are, you'll have to show me I.D.
当然 小姐 请看一下
Of course, young lady. Look at this for me, please.
- 别再闪了 好吗？- 怎么了？
- Would you stop that? - What?
那个会害她得脑癌的
That thing will give her brain cancer.
她没被伤害过
Never hurt her before. Close the doors.
特勤组快到了
Special Services will be here.
你闪了那可怜的女人几次?
How many times have you flashy-thinged that woman?
两次
Couple.
- 你不担心造成长期影响? - 有一点
- Don't you worry about long-term damage? - A little.
- 你闪过我吗? - 没有
- Have you flashy-thinged me? - No.
说真的! 有没有闪过我？
I ain't playing with you! Have you?
以后清除记忆的事交给我
I think I should be in charge of the flashy thing.
有我在休想
Not while I'm around.
你会烧坏别人的脑袋
You'll fricassee someone's brain.
有两个死了的外星人而且 验尸官需要新记忆
We got two dead aliens and a medical examiner needs a new memory.
给她个快乐的记忆
Make it a happy memory.
它到底在哪里?
Where is it?!
喂 Z...
Hey, Zed.
...这里的人都不睡觉?
Doesn't anybody ever get any sleep around here?
孪生子让我们守圣塔伦时间 那一天有37小时
The twins keep us on Centurian time. It's a 37-hour day.
过几个月就会习惯
Give it a few months. You'll get used to it.
或者你会精神错乱
Or have a psychotic episode.
这是猎户座
Here's Orion.
是北方天空最亮的星群
It's a grouping of the brightest stars in the northern sky.
- 这是猎户星带 - 那个小人就是这么说:
- Here's Orion's belt. - The little guy said:
"避免战争 银河系在猎户座星带"
"To prevent war, the Galaxy is on Orion's belt."
小子 猎户星带上没银河系
There are no galaxies on Orion's belt.
星带就是这3颗星 银河系是很大的
The belt is just these three stars. Galaxies are huge.
有几十亿颗星 你听错了
They're made up of billions of stars. You heard wrong.
随你说 我知道我听到什么
Look, whatever, I know what I heard.
很漂亮
Pretty lady.
糟老头的故事渐渐的显现了
That grumpy guy's story's starting to come into focus a little bit here.
献花给外星人的人就是你
So you were the guy in that picture with the flowers?
我猜她一直没收到花
And, I take it, she never got those flowers.
她结婚了吗?
So, what, she ever get married or anything?
有人说 轰轰烈烈的爱
They say it's better to have loved and lost...
...胜于没爱过
...than never to have loved at all.
你试试
Try it.
看看这个
Look at this.
他们都在离境
They're all leaving.
刚逃走了12个人 烈擎打头阵
We've had 12 jumps in the last hour. Redgick was just the first.
他们获悉什么 我们不知道的情报?
What do they know that we don't?
老鼠为何弃船而逃?
Why does a rat desert a ship?
让我看4号卫星显示 质子热感应显像
Give me Lem Sat 4, please, with a proton induction thermoscan.
谢谢 18号卫星
Thank you. Okay. Lem Sat 18.
好 4000号
All right, 4000.
是亚基伦战舰
An Arquillian battle cruiser.
而亚基伦王子死在地球上
And we've got a dead Arquillian prince.
说到这个恶棍...
Speak of the devil.
听起来他们气坏了
They sound pissed.
快翻译出来 快
Translate that. Step on it.
去洛辛保珠宝店搜一搜 看能找出什么
Go to Rosenberg's jewellery store, and see what you can turn up.
给他个武器
Give the kid a weapon.
- 原子4号枪 - 就是我要的
- Series 4 De-atomizer. - That's what I'm talking about.
小蟋蟀
Noisy Cricket.
K 不 别这样
Kay, no, no, come on, man.
你拿原子4号...
You get a Series 4 De-atomizer...
...我拿小蟋蟀?
...I get a little midget Cricket?
感觉上一捏就碎了
Feel like I'm gonna break it.
这是我的卡车!
Hey, this is my truck!
记得领车时跟他们说
Make sure you tell them that down at the impound.
拜托
Please.
谁闯入珠宝店却不偷珠宝?
Who breaks into a jewellery store and leaves the jewels?
要找的不是珠宝
Somebody not looking for jewellery.
这家伙真爱他的猫
This guy had a serious crush on his cat.
伏下
Get down!
老天!
Man!
是他 是那个虫族!
That's him. That's the bug!
穿着雅加衣!
In the Edgar suit!
别在众目睽睽下开枪!
We do not discharge our weapons in view of the public!
我们没时间讨论这个!
We ain't got time for this bullshit!
外星人的战舰就要...
There's a alien battle cruiser about to...
总有战舰 死光枪...
There's always an alien battle cruiser or a death ray...
...或是银河黑死病入侵地球
...or an intergalactic plague about to wipe out life on Earth.
人类快乐过日子因为...
The only way people get on with their happy lives...
...他们并不知情!
...is they do not know about it!
别担心那只虫
And don't worry about the bug.
他走不了 船在我们手上
He's not leaving town. We got his ship.
派封锁队来...
We need a containment crew...
...到麦道格街
... on MacDougal Street.
封锁是个好主意了 但外星人还在继续离开
Containment may be a moot point. The exodus continues.
就像是舞会结束了 最后走要的付帐
The party's over, and the last one to leave gets stuck with the check.
忘恩负义的!
You sorry little ingrates!
那亚基伦战舰呢?
What about the Arquillians?
翻出部分的讯息是:交出银河系
We've translated part of the message: " Deliver the Galaxy."
- 他们要得不多 不是吗? - 有更好的
- They don't want much, do they? - Oh, it gets better.
他们要我们负责
They hold us responsible.
(黑超特警交出银河系)
你把死人放在哪里?
Where do you keep your dead?
我没有死人
I don't have any dead.
在哪里?
Where?
不知道
I don't know.
在市殓房吗?
The city morgue?
那些3张1块钱 先生
That's three for a dollar, sir!
因为金星的光反射在...
It was some light that refracted off of Venus...
...沼泽气上...
...into some swamp gas...
...所以会...
...and that's what made the...
好了 小子!
All right, kid!
失陪 怎么了?
Excuse me. What's up?
亚基伦人要银河系 不管那是什么意思
The Arquillians want the Galaxy, whatever that means.
需要精通银河系的专家帮忙
We need help, a professional...
...一个对星际政治有经验的人
...with years of experience in intergalactic politics.
希望那家伙还没离城
I hope the little twerp hasn't skipped town.
大家聚到这里...
If you'll gather over here...
聚到这里 再近一点
That's right, move in closer. That's good. Thanks.
请大家看这里 谢谢
If you look right here, I'd appreciate it. Thank you.
伪装真差 一看就是外星人
The worst disguise ever. He's definitely an alien.
不喜欢? 谁在乎啊!
You don't like it, you can kiss my furry butt.
你忙吗?
Busy, Frank?
抱歉没空 我的太空船要开了
Can't talk now. My flight's leaving in...
开始吧!
Get your paws off!
叫捕狗队来!
Call the pound!
狗欠我朋友钱
The dog owes my friend money.
关于亚基伦和虫族 你知道什么?
Arquillians and bugs, what do you know?
- 不知道 - 不知道?
- Nothing. - Not a thing?
停 停! 好!
Stop, stop, stop it! Okay, okay!
洛辛保不只是亚基伦人
Rosenberg wasn't a two-bit Arquillian.
他是银河系的管理人 他以为在地球会安全
He was the guardian of the Galaxy. He thought he'd be safe on Earth.
虫族有另外的计划
The bug had other plans.
银河系是宇宙次原子能源 的最好来源
The Galaxy is the best source for subatomic energy in the universe.
若虫族取得 亚基伦人就完了
If the bugs get it, kiss the Arquillians goodbye.
问星带的事
Ask about the belt.
他说银河系在猎户座星带上 是什么意思?
Rosenberg mentioned Orion's belt. What did he mean?
- 考倒我了 - 考倒你了？
- Beats me. - Beats you?
别摇了!
Not around.
他在练习腹语
It's a ventriloquist act.
银河系在这里!
The Galaxy is here!
什么意思?
Here?
银河系十亿颗星怎会在这里?
A galaxy's millions of stars and planets.
你们什么时候才了解到 尺寸不是问题?
When will you learn that size doesn't matter?
重要的东西也可以很小
If something's important, it doesn't mean it's not small.
多小?
How small?
像弹珠或珠宝
The size of a marble or a jewel.
抱歉 我要在赶太空船之前走一走
Excuse me. I gotta be walked before my flight.
快离开这里
Get out of here.
银河系在这 不是在猎户座星带上
If the Galaxy's here, it's not on Orion's belt.
你想引人注意...
When you want attention...
猎户座
Orion.
很好听的名字
That's a pretty name.
这是什么?
What's this?
是的 很好 谢谢
Yes, good, thank you.
谢谢你确定铃没坏
Thank you for making sure the bell works.
农夫 有什么事?
What's up, Farmer John?
有个人来这里
A man came in here earlier.
一个死人
A dead man.
与我何干?
And that means what to me?
他是我的好友
It was a very dear friend of mine.
有只动物跟他一起
I believe he had an animal with him.
是我送他的礼物 一只猫
It was a gift I gave him. A pet cat.
对我来说非常的重要
It means worlds to me.
我想要回来
I'd like to have it back.
我需要身份证... ...宠物拥有人证明...
I'll need picture I.D., proof of ownership of the cat...
...与死人亲属关系 的公证证明
...notarized proof of kinship with the deceased.
别这样
Don't do that.
哪样?
Do what?
别打
Don't do it.
天啊!
Oh, man.
K 交给我就行了
Look, Kay, let me handle this one.
不过是抓猫 不难的
All we gotta do is get a cat. It's not that hard.
如果你进去 你又会对她闪个不停
But if you go in there, you'll start flashing your brain ray in her face.
会害她得血癌
She'll wind up with leukemia.
医生不需要你把她学的都洗掉 我只要五分钟
The doctor don't need you flashing away her med-school classes. Five minutes.
两分钟
Two minutes.
那只猫呢?
Where's the animal?
我说了 不知道
I said I don't know.
我们去找
Well, let's see if we can find it.
你好
Hello!
嗨!
- 你好吗? - 你好
- How you doing? - Hello.
我是弗莱迪警官 26支局来的
I'm Sergeant Friday from the 26th Precinct.
有只猫跟尸体一起被送来
A cat came in with a corpse the other day.
- 名牌上是写着猎户座 - 是的
- "Orion" on the nametag? - Right.
这只猫...
Well, this cat is a witness...
...是谋杀案...的证人 我要带它走
...in a murder case. I'll need to take him.
我不知道猫在哪里
I don't know where the cat is.
不知道?
You don't?
但你可以带我跟你走
No, but maybe you could take me with you instead.
你还真主动
Damn, you do start fast, don't you?
我真的想跟你走
I'd really like to go with you...
...就是现在!
...now.
为什么?
And exactly why is that?
我有东西要给你看
I need to show you something.
慢点
Slow down.
- 你不可以这么快! - 你没搞明白
- Girl, don't hit the gas like that! - You don't understand.
你一定要看这个
You really need to see this.
我会 只有一件事
I will. One thing.
我来驾车 这不是雄纠纠的任务
I gotta drive. It's not some macho trip.
我在说这是我的习惯
That's just the way I get down.
色鬼 你没搞懂
Look, stud, you're really not getting this.
我需要你帮助我
There's something I need you to help me with.
别动!
Freeze it!
你真迟钝!
You are thick!
我怎么会知道?
How could I know?
说得还不够清楚?
Did I have to sing it?
你像在勾引我...
You were like a drunk prom date.
真是的! 女人显示出性独立...
Typical. Anytime a woman shows even a hint of sexual independence...
闭嘴!
Shut up!
放开她 吃屎的!
Let her go!
听好 猴仔...
Listen, monkey-boy...
...跟你比起来我们进化多了
...l'm on the top rung of the evolutionary ladder.
所以闭嘴
So can it.
让我看你的脸 然后我会把你的病治好
Show me your face, and I'll cure your ills.
拔过苍蝇的翅膀吗? 想过苍蝇会报仇吗?
Ever pull wings off a fly? Care to see the fly get even?
那你的船呢?
What about your ship?
你没太空船 已经被没收了
If that's what you call that trash we got locked up.
- 放下武器! - 休想
- Put your weapons down! - Won't happen.
没关系
It's okay.
怎么会没关系?
How is it okay?
我是说将会没事
I'm saying it's gonna be okay.
别太肯定 混球
Don't bet on it, meat sack.
放我走!
Let me go!
进去!
Go on!
带我去这里
Take me here.
休想
No way.
带我去!
Take me!
他上了计程车
He's in a cab!
别动...
Don't move! Don't move! Don't move!
嗨 这位先生 什么?
Hey, man, what?
搭计程车逃不出地球 走! 跟我来!
He's not leaving the planet in a cab. Let's go.
启动曼哈顿侦测网
Put up a bionet all the way around Manhattan.
不是人类就别想离开!
If it's not human, it doesn't leave.
亚基伦战舰怎么说?
What do we hear from upstairs?
一样 交出银河系
" Deliver the Galaxy."
虫族拿走银河系 但我们有他的船
The bug's got the Galaxy, but we got his ship.
警告! 质子武器威胁
Warning: Plutonic fusion detection.
质子武器开动
- 为什么开枪打我们? - 亚基伦战争规则
- Why are they shooting at us? - Battle rules.
他们下了最后通牒 然后示警弹
We get an ultimatum, a warning shot,
之后要在银河1周时间回覆
then a galactic week to respond.
银河1周是多久?
A galactic week? How the hell long is that?
1小时
One hour.
1小时?
One hour?
然后呢?
Then what?
狗屎!
That's bullshit!
为了不让虫族得手 亚基伦人会毁了它
To keep the bugs from getting it, Arquillians will destroy that galaxy.
和它所在的星球
And whatever planet it's on.
你指的是我们
You're talking about us.
很讨厌吧?
Sucks, huh?
搜索1百里以内的太空船
I'll get the location of every interstellar vehicle.
搜过了 法兰克搭上最后一艘船
I already did. Frank took the last ship.
- 史尼登机场与史龙码头 - 走了
- Sneden's Landing and Throg's Neck. - Gone.
- 大西洋城 - 走了
- What about Atlantic City? - Gone.
- 巴瑞欧站? - 走了
- Bayonne? - Gone.
- 还有三里岛 - 走了
- There's Three Mile Island. - Gone.
- 史坦登岛! - 走了 谢天谢地
- Staten Island? - Gone, thank God.
时间紧迫虫人若离开...
We're running out of time. If that bug gets off Earth, we're bug food.
嘿! 老头!
Hey, old guys!
那还能用吗?
Do those still work?
- 你跟我来 - 什么?
- You're coming with me. - What?
长途飞行 我要点心
It's a long trip. I'll need a snack.
你要走隧道?
The tunnel?
- 还有别条路到皇后区? - 隧道会塞车!
- You know a better way to Queens? - It'll be packed!
(皇后区隧道)
记得红色按纽吗?
Remember the red button?
按红色按纽
Push the red button.
最好绑安全带
Put on a seat belt.
你太紧张了 年轻人放轻松
You're much too tense. You're young. Relax.
放轻松 享受工作上的乐趣
Take some joy in your work.
喜欢音乐吗?
Do you like music?
(猫王)
这样好多了
That's better.
你知道猫王己死了?
You do know Elvis is dead?
没有 猫王没死 他回家了
No, Elvis is not dead. He just went home.
你不会想吃我
You don't wanna eat me.
我是地球上的重要人物 我是皇后
I'm an important person on my planet. Like a queen!
是女神 大家膜拜我
A goddess, even. There are those who worship me.
我只是想让你知道
I'm not trying to impress you.
这样会引起战争
I'm just saying it could start a war!
战争才好 我家人就有的吃的了
Good, war. That means more food for my family.
全部7千8百万的人 有许多张嘴要吃东西
All 78 million of them. That's a lot of mouths to feed.
你是个好爸爸 但我要留在这!
You're a wonderful dad, but I'm staying here!
那就是我的意思
Now, that's what I'm talking about.
蟑螂来了
Roaches check in.
休想离开
They don't check out.
警告! 地球8分钟后毁灭
Warning: E ight minutes to the destruction of Earth.
8分钟后...
E ight minutes...
...毁灭
... to destruction.
我们用内爆第五级电波
We'll use pulsar level five with an implosion factor.
什么? !
What?!
数到三就射击 一...
Just shoot the damn thing on the count of three. One...
...二...三
...Two ...Three
白痴!
You idiots!
你根本就不懂!
You don't get it!
我赢了
I've won.
结束了
It's over.
吃奶的蠢货!
You're milk-suckers!
你们不重要
You don't matter.
几秒钟后你们都不会碍事了
In a few seconds, you won't even be matter.
你因违反星际法被捕了
You're under arrest for violating the Tycho Treaty.
交出你手上的银河系...
So hand over whatever galaxy you might be carrying...
...然后把手放到头上
...and put your hands on your head.
我把手...
I'll put my hands...
...放到头上
...on my head.
像这样?
Like this?
这不在我的计划中
That did not go the way I planned.
不要让它上第二条船
Don't let him on the second ship.
- 你说什么? - 别让他离开地球!
- What are you talking about? - Keep him on this planet.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
去拿回我的枪
I'm gonna get my gun back.
喂 虫人!
Hey, bug!
我跟你说话! 知道我用报纸杀过
You know how many of your kind I've swatted with a paper?
多少像你一样的虫子?
You're just a smear on the sports page...
...你这个黏哒哒的 专吃内脏的寄生虫
...you slimy, gut-sucking, intestinal parasite!
吃我!
Eat me!
怎么了?
What's up?
吃完就想逃? 不吃甜品了?
You just gonna eat and run? What about dessert?
就这样?
That's it?
你要去哪? 现在好戏才刚要上场!
Where you going? This party's just getting started.
你要去哪?
Where you going?
听好
Let me tell you.
只有一个方法离开这星球 就是必须经过我这关
There's only one way off this planet, and that's through me.
你去哪里?
Where you going?
你以为你赢了?
Why you running, huh?
我还站着的
I'm still standing.
快 拿来 拿来
Come on, bring it. Bring it!
抱歉 那是你的姑妈吗?
I'm sorry. Was that your auntie?
这表示这是你舅舅
That means that's your uncle.
你们长得都一样
You all look alike.
瞧瞧
Well, well.
大坏虫有颗脆弱的心
Big, bad bug got a bit of a soft spot, huh?
我不明白的是...
I can't understand why you gotta...
...你为什么要带人来这
...come down here bringing all this ruckus...
制造混乱夺取银河系?
...snatching up galaxies and everything.
我的态度是不找麻烦 就没麻烦
My attitude is, don't start nothing, won't be nothing.
快从我的面前消失 免得麻烦上身
Ease up out of my face before something bad happens to you.
太迟了
Too late.
告诉亚基伦人 我们拿到银河系了
Tell the Arquillians we have the Galaxy.
知道了
You got it, friend.
要把枪拿回来 是吗?
Going to get your gun back, huh?
我喜欢这把枪
I like this gun.
你在里面鬼混 害的我一个人在忙
While you was in there playing around, I was doing all the work.
我先用石头打他的头
I had to bean him in the head with this big rock.
本来想用木板打他
I was gonna hit him with a 2-by-4.
它踢我 好痛
He kicked me. It hurt.
我拿起火来吓他
But then I got to the fire. I was like that with it.
工作第二天表现不错
Not bad for your second day of work, is it?
这是我遇过最怪异的情况
This definitely rates a 9.0 on my weird-shit-o-metre.
你该看看在1968年 麦格逊人迁移时
Should've been here for the Zeronion migration in 1968.
你还没出生吧!
I guess you weren't even alive in '68.
很有趣的工作
Interesting job you guys have.
我知道有规矩...
I know we got these rules...
...但她协助我们杀了那只虫
...but she did help us bust that bug.
也许不必清除她的记忆
Maybe we didn't have to flashy-thing her.
她会跟谁说? 她成天跟死人为伍
Come on. Who will she tell? She hang out with dead people.
不是给她的
It's not for her.
是给我的
It's for me.
什么?
What?
很美吧?
Aren't they beautiful?
星星
Stars.
我很久没观赏 其实它们很...
I never look at them anymore, but they actually are...
...迷人
...beautiful.
你把你的伙伴吓坏了
Kay, you're frightening your partner.
我在训练接班人 不是拍档
I've been training a replacement, not a partner.
K 等一下
Wait a minute, Kay.
我一人无法胜任
I cannot do this job by myself.
两位! 我的寓所离这里很远
Guys, my apartment isn't anywhere near here.
甚至不在这个岛上
It's not even on the same island.
日期...
Days...
...月份...
...months...
...年份
...years.
不要朝着自己
Always face it forward.
我刚从蟑螂肚里出来
I was in an interstellar cockroach's gullet.
是100个最不愿记得的记忆之一
That's one of 100 memories I don't want.
再见
See you around.
不...
No...
...你不会的
...you won't.
(底特律汽车向地心引力挑战)
(纽约棒球队 内野手说: 飞碟害我漏接)
(一个男人昏迷35年后重回女友怀抱)
嗨 J
Hey J,
Z说索里领事要...
The high consulate from Solaxium 9...
...公牛队的票
...wants seats for the Bulls game.
通知洛曼 他是索里星人
Call Dennis Rodman. He's from that planet.
洛曼? 你在开玩笑吗?
Rodman? You're kidding.
不是
Nope.
并没有怎么掩饰嘛
Not much of a disguise.